Guide to the Cornell University Jewelry And Silver, 1892-1955.
Cornell University Jewelry And Silver
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Jewelry And Silver, 1892-1955.
47-7-3438
Cornell University.
28 items.
Jewelry and silver items.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Various Cornell related jewelry and silver items, including rings and pins, hat pins, locket, watch fobs, spoons (Cornell spoons and grapefruit spoons), Cornell miniature silver-plate mug.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Various Cornell related jewelry and silver items, including rings, pins, hat pins, bracelets, a locket, watch fobs, spoons (Cornell spoons and grapefruit spoons), Cornell miniature silver-plate mug.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University -- Insignia.; Cornell University
Subjects:
Insignia
Form and Genre Terms:
Jewelry.; Spoons.; Grapefruit spoons.; Hatpins.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Cornell University hat pin, profile of E. Cornell, banded red and white (gift of Esther L. Casselman - Sanborn, NY), MU-355 (Box 1)
- Silver Cornell oar hat-pin, owned by Maude Moore Bland (1882-1963), MU-2064 (Box 1)
- Men's Cornell stick pin, MU-1144 (Box 1)
- Cornell pin, red and white with bust of E. Cornell - from William G. Hanes, Los Angeles, by way of the President's Office, MU-738 (Box 1)
- Sennightly Club pin, MU-1349 (Box 1)
- Gold tie pin, MU-971 (Box 1)
- Gold class ring, Class of 1925, gold with red stone, “C 25” (belonged to Lois Dusinbury), MU-760 (Box 1)
- Locket with Cornell Seal - contains portraits of two women, possibly sisters, MU-954 (Box 1)
- 1918 watch fob, MU-968 (Box 1)
- Walter H. Tyler ’28 watch fob, MU-1348 (Box 1)
- Silver bracelet with winter sports scenes, MU-1153 (Box 1)
- Silver bracelet with Cornell emblem, MU-1154 (Box 1)
- Thin, gold plated bracelet with small Cornell Seal, MU-1552 (Box 1)
- Silver spoon - handle in the shape of a woman holding up the Cornell Seal, MU-1331 (Box 1)
- Silver grapefruit spoon (“Cornell” on bowl), MU-903 (Box 1)
- 2 Balch silver grapefruit spoons, MU-1346-MU-1347 (Box 1)
- 5 silver Statler "S" demitasse spoons, donated by Irene Patterson, MU-1531-1535 (Box 1)
- 3 silver McGraw Tower demitasse spoons, donated by Irene Patterson (larger version - MU-1539), MU-1536-1538 (Box 1)
- Silver spoon, handle has image of McGraw Tower (small version - MU-1536-1538), MU-1539 (Box 1)
- Silver "Adelaide Hunter Hoodless" demitasse spoon, donated by Irene Patterson, MU-1132 (Box 1)
- Cornell miniature silver-plate mug, ca. 1909, MU-1367 (Box 1)